Inventory of the Paul B. Henze papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Horn of Africa File, 1959-2009 (Box 59-143)
  - Writings by others, 1961-2008
    - Petterson, Donald, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 87: 14-15)
    - Porter, Bruce D., 1979 (Box-folder 87: 16)
    - Remnek, Richard B., 1980, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 87: 17-18)
    - Right, M.V., 1980s (Box-folder 87: 19)
    - Seifu Michael Zewde, 1982 (Box-folder 88: 1)
    - Sherr, E.S., 1980s (Box-folder 88: 2)
    - Shibeshi Lemma, 1986 June (Box-folder 88: 3)
    - Shinn, David, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 88: 4-5)
    - Sintayehu Kassaye, 2006-2007 (Box-folder 88: 6)
    - Sisay Asefa, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 88: 7-8)
    - Sorenson, John, 1990 (Box-folder 88: 9)
    - Taffara Deguefe, 2000 (Box-folder 88: 10-11)
    - Taye Tilahun, 1989 (Box-folder 88: 12)
    - Tekie Fessehatzion, 1989 August (Box-folder 88: 13)
    - Tesfa Guma, 1991 October (Box-folder 88: 14)
    - Tesfaye Asfaw, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 88: 15-16)
    - Tesfaye Demeke, 1982 (Box-folder 88: 17)
    - Tessore, Alberto, 1984 (Box-folder 88: 18)
    - Tsadkan Gebre Tensae, 1993 (Box-folder 88: 19)
    - Tsegaye Hailu, 1987 June (Box-folder 88: 20)
    - Uspenskii, Porfirii, undated (Box-folder 89: 1-2)
      Photocopy of his Vostok khristianskii.
    - Van Voorst, Bruce, 1978 (Box-folder 89: 3)
    - Vestal, Theodore M., 1994 (Box-folder 89: 4)
    - Waldron, Sidney, 1982-1987 (Box-folder 89: 5)
    - Warden, Gail, 2000 (Box-folder 89: 6)
    - Zewde Gabre-Sellassie, 1975, 2000 (Box-folder 89: 7-8)
  - Conference materials, 1978-2009
    Contains correspondence, notes, conference papers, reports and photographs. Arranged in chronological order by conference date.
    - 5th International Conference on Ethiopian Studies, University of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois, 1978 April 13-16 (Box-folder 90: 1-2)
    - Discussion Group on the Horn of Africa and Persian Gulf, Council on Foreign Relations, 1980 April 17 (Box-folder 90: 3)
    - 7th International Conference on Ethiopian Studies, Lund, Sweden, 1982 April 26-29 (Box-folder 90: 4-5)
    - 8th International Conference of Ethiopian Studies, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, 1984 November 26-30 (Box-folder 90: 6-10)
    - "Ethiopia Revisited: A Seminar with John H. Spencer," Center for Strategic and International Studies, Washington, DC, 1986 May 7 (Box-folder 90: 11)
    - 9th International Conference of Ethiopian Studies, Moscow, Russia, 1986 August 26-29 (Box-folder 91: 1)
    - First International Conference on the History of Ethiopian Art, Royal Asiatic Society, London, England, 1986 October 21-22 (Box-folder 91: 2-3)
      Includes negatives and slides of Ethiopian artifacts for a lecture by Paul Henze.
    - International Symposium on the Centenary of Addis Ababa, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, 1986 November 24-25 (Box-folder 91: 4)
    - Workshop on the Problems and Prospects of National Unity in the Sudan, Wilson Center, Washington, DC, 1987 February 16-17 (Box-folder 91: 5)
    - Trends in the Horn of Africa Conference, Arlington, Virginia, 1987 February 25-26 (Box-folder 91: 6)
    - Meeting on Anti-Communist Insurgencies, Foreign Policy Research Institute, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1987 May 1 (Box-folder 91: 7)
    - International Experts' Meeting on Domestic Savings Mobilization through Formal and Informal Sectors: Comparative Experiences in Asian and African Developing Countries, East-West Center, Honolulu, Hawaii, 1987 June 2-4 (Box-folder 91: 8)
    - "Crisis in the Horn of Africa: Causes and Prospects," Wilson Center, Washington, DC, 1987 June 17-20 (Box-folder 91: 9-11)
    - "The Military and the Third World," sponsored by the Triangle Universities Security Seminar, Durham, North Carolina, 1987 October 30-31 (Box-folder 91: 12)
    - Conference on Ethiopia, Freedom House, New York, New York, 1988 May 14 (Box-folder 92: 1)
    - 10th Ethiopian Studies Conference, Paris, France, 1988 August 13-16 (Box-folder 92: 2-6)
    - Fifth Conference of Northeastern African Studies, "Peace and Stability in the Horn of Africa," East Lansing, Michigan, 1989 April 26-28 (Box-folder 92: 7-8)
    - Roundtable discussion on Ethiopia, Orkand Corporation, Silver Spring, Maryland, 1989 November 9 (Box-folder 92: 9)
    - Study Group on the Horn of Africa, Council on Foreign Relations, New York, 1990 February 6 (Box-folder 93: 1)
    - Conference on International Relations in the Horn of Africa, Cairo, Egypt, 1990 May 27-30 (Box-folder 93: 2)
    - Regional Security Conference, International Institute for Strategic Studies London and Centre for Political Research and Studies, Cairo, Egypt, 1990 May 27-30 (Box-folder 93: 3-4)
    - African Water Summit, Cairo, Egypt, 1990 June 24-27 (Box-folder 93: 5)
    - Ethiopian Research Council, First Annual Convention, College Park, Maryland, 1990 August 31 (Box-folder 93: 6)
    - International Conference on Eritrea, sponsored by Eritreans for Peace and Democracy, Baltimore, Maryland, 1990 November 3-4 (Box-folder 93: 7)
    - International Colloquium, "Die Aktuelle Lage in Åthiopien," Bonn, Germany, 1990 November 30 (Box-folder 93: 8)
    - "The Way to Peace in the Horn of Africa: Federalism and Its Alternatives," University of Leicester, 1990 December 17-19 (Box-folder 93: 9)
    - XIth International Conference of Ethiopian Studies, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, 1991 April 1-6 (Box-folder 93: 10)
    - "Changing Realities in the Horn of Africa: Implications for Africa and U.S. Policy," sponsored by the Stanley Foundation, Warrenton, Virginia, 1991 October 24-26 (Box-folder 93: 11)
    - "The Horn of Africa: Its Political and Economic Future," School of Oriental and African Studies, University of London, 1991 November 28 (Box-folder 93: 12)
    - "Symposium on Rehabilitating the Ethiopian Economy," InterAfrica Group, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, 1992 January 15-18 (Box-folder 94: 1)
    - "The Horn of Africa: Changing Realities and U.S. Response," Congressional Research Service, Washington, D.C., 1992 March 19-20 (Box-folder 94: 2-3)
    - Symposium on Environmental Degradation, jointly sponsored by Tigray Development Association and the Relief Society of Tigray, Mek'ele, Ethiopia, 1992 April 15-20 (Box-folder 94: 4)
    - "Peace and Stability in Northeast Africa," Africa Studies Center, Michigan State University, East Lansing, Michigan, 1992 April 23-25 (Box-folder 94: 5)
    - "Horn of Africa Exhibition Planning," Kellogg Center, Michigan State University, East Lansing, Michigan, 1992 April 26-27 (Box-folder 94: 6)
    - "Uniting Ethiopian World Scholars and Creative Artists," Ethiopian Research Council Convention, Florida State University, Tallahassee, Florida, 1993 September 9-12 (Box-folder 94: 7)
    - Third International Conference on the History of Ethiopian Art, Institute of Ethiopian Studies, Addis Ababa University, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, 1993 November 9-11 (Box-folder 94: 8-10)
    - "New Visions of the Horn of Africa," School of Oriental and African Studies, University of London, London, England, 1994 April 14-15 (Box-folder 94: 11)
    - Third International Social Studies Conference, Nairobi, Kenya, 1994 June 27-29 (Box-folder 94: 12)
    - Tenth Annual Strategy and National Security Conference, Center for International Affairs, Harvard University, Cape Cod, Massachusetts, 1995 June 15-17 (Box-folder 95: 1)
    - Conference on Ethiopia's Future, Bureau of Intelligence and Research, U.S. Department of State, Washington, D.C., 1995 October 31 (Box-folder 95: 2-3)
    - Adwa Victory Centenary Conference, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, 1996 February 26-March 2 (Box-folder 95: 4)
    - "The Nile: Civilizations, History, Myths," Tel Aviv University, 1997 May 19-22 (Box-folder 95: 5-9)
      Includes photographs of conference participants.
    - XIIIth International Conference of Ethiopian Studies, Kyoto, Japan, 1997 December 12-17 (Box-folder 95: 10)
    - 5th International Conference on the History of Ethiopian Art, Lisbon, Portugal, 1999 October 27-30 (Box-folder 95: 11-12)
    - 6th Orbis Aethiopicus conference, "Ethiopia: A Living Example for Inter-Cultural Collaboration," Frankfurt, Germany, 2000 October 27-29 (Box-folder 96: 1)
      Includes photographs of Henze.
    - XIVth International Conference of Ethiopian Studies, Institute of Ethiopian Studies, Addis Ababa, 2000 November 6-11 (Box-folder 96: 2-3)
    - International Conference on Contemporary Development Issues in Ethiopia, Ethiopian American Foundation, Kalamazoo, Michigan, 2001 August 16-18 (Box-folder 96: 4)
    - 7th Orbis Aethiopicus conference, Essen, Germany, 2001 October 14 (Box-folder 96: 5)
    - 1st International Littmann conference, "Archaeology and History of the Horn of Africa," Munich, Germany, 2002 May 2-5 (Box-folder 96: 6)
    - VI International Conference on the History of Ethiopian Art, Institute of Ethiopian Studies, Addis Ababa, 2002 November 5-8 (Box-folder 96: 7)
    - International Symposium on Contemporary Development Issues in Ethiopia, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, 2003 July 11-12 (Box-folder 96: 8)
    - 15th International Conference of Ethiopian Studies, Hamburg University, Hamburg, Germany, 2003 July 21-25 (Box-folder 96: 9-10)
    - 8th Orbis Aethiopicus Conference, "Continuity and Innovation in Ethiopian Culture," Cambridge, England, 2003 September 12-14 (Box-folder 97: 1)
    - Third International Symposium on Ethiopian Development Studies, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, 2005 June 18-19 (Box-folder 97: 2)
    - "Future of Democratization in Ethiopia," Bureau of Intelligence and Research, U.S. Department of State, Washington, DC, 2005 December 12 (Box-folder 97: 3)
    - 2nd International Littmann Conference, Aksum, Ethiopia, 2006 January 6-12 (Box-folder 97: 4-5)
    - Research workshop, "Narrating the Nile: Cultures, Identities, Memories," Tel Aviv University, Tel Aviv, Israel, 2006 May 28-31 (Box-folder 97: 6-8)
    - Littmann Conference, Berlin, Germany, 2009 April 1-4 (Box-folder 97: 9)
  - Travel files, 1971-2007
    Correspondence, memoranda, notes, business cards, reports, receipts, clippings, tourism information, and itineraries. Unless otherwise indicated, travel is to Ethiopia. Arranged chronologically.
    - 1971-1972 (Box-folder 98: 1)
    - 1977 (Box-folder 98: 2)
    - 1981 January-February (Box-folder 98: 3)
    - 1987 March-April (Box-folder 98: 4-7)
      Includes photographs of landscapes, food relief bags, and a crowd of young people.
    - 1987 June (Box-folder 98: 8)
      Munich, Germany.
    - 1988 March (Box-folder 98: 9)
      Ethiopia and Somalia.
    - 1989 February-March (Box-folder 98: 10)
    - 1990 November-December (Box-folder 98: 11)
    - 1991 June-July (Box-folder 98: 12)
    - 1992 January-February (Box-folder 99: 1-3)
    - 1993 March-May (Box-folder 99: 4)
    - 1993 November-December (Box-folder 99: 5)
    - 1995 January-March (Box-folder 99: 6-7)
      Ethiopia and Eritrea.
    - 1996 February-April (Box-folder 99: 8-10)
    - 1997 February-March (Box-folder 99: 11)
    - 1998 February (Box-folder 100: 1-4)
    - 1999 March-April (Box-folder 100: 5-9)
      Includes photographs of Henze and slides of the Debre Libanos monastery.
    - 2000 May and November (Box-folder 100: 10-12)
      Includes oil pastels by Berhanu Alebachew.
    - 2001 October-December (Box-folder 101: 1-3)
    - 2002 November-December (Box-folder 101: 4-8)
      Includes photograph of Henze.
    - 2004 March (Box-folder 101: 9)
    - 2005 June (Box-folder 101: 10)
    - 2006 January-February (Box-folder 101: 11-12)
    - 2007 September (Box-folder 101: 13-15)
      Includes photographs of Henze in Ethiopia with unidentified men.
  - Research materials, 1959-2009
    - Cuba, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 102: 1)
      Includes transcript of conversation between Fidel Castro and Erich Honecker on Ethiopia.
    - Djibouti, 1981-1989 (Box-folder 102: 2)
    - Eritrea, 1974-1999 (Box-folder 102: 3-16)
      Includes materials related to the 1993 referendum on independence from Ethiopia.
    - Eritrea, 2000-2009 (Box-folder 103: 1-4)
    - Ethiopia, 1959-2009
      - General, 2001-2005 (Box-folder 103: 5-9)
      - Agriculture, 1965-1995 (Box-folder 104: 1-16, Folder 105: 1)
      - Aksum, 1999-2006 (Box-folder 105: 2)
      - Amharic language and literature, 1960s-1980s (Box-folder 105: 3-5)
      - Anthropology, 1994-2006 (Box-folder 105: 6-12)
      - Archaeology, 1970-2009 (Box-folder 105: 13-19)
      - Architecture, undated (Box-folder 106: 1)
      - Art, 1969-2005, undated (Box-folder 106: 2-12)
        Includes slides of religious and folk art and an inventory of art at the U.S. Embassy in Addis Ababa.
      - Battle of Adwa, 1996, undated (Box-folder 106: 13)
      - Bibliographies, 1970s-1992 (Box-folder 106: 14-15)
      - Border conflict with Eritrea, 1998-2009 (Box-folder 107: 1-3)
      - Chronologies of Ethiopian revolution, 1971-1977 (Box-folder 107: 4-8)
      - Churches, 1971-2006 (Box-folder 107: 9-10)
      - Constitution, 1986-1995 (Box-folder 108: 1-3)
        Includes correspondence from the Constitutional Commission.
      - Democracy, 1991-2006 (Box-folder 108: 4-9)
        Includes correspondence.
      - Derg, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 108: 10)
      - Development, 1967-2002 (Box-folder 109: 1-12)
      - Economy, 1975-1996 (Box-folder 110: 1-9)
      - Education, 1987-1993 (Box-folder 110: 10-13)
      - Elections, 1992, 2005 (Box-folder 111: 1-9)
        Includes photographs, correspondence and observer reports.
      - Falashas, 1972-1994 (Box-folder 112: 1-3)
      - Famine, 1973-1991 (Box-folder 112: 4-7)
      - Forestry, 1959 (Box-folder 112: 8)
      - Graziani, Rudolfo, 2004 (Box-folder 112: 9)
      - Gunda Gunde, 1968-2003 (Box-folder 112: 10-11)
      - Haile Selassie, 1971-1977 (Box-folder 113: 1-2)
      - Harar, 2006 (Box-folder 113: 3)
      - Human Rights, 1978-1996 (Box-folder 113: 4-5)
      - Irob, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 113: 6)
      - Islam, 2004 (Box-folder 113: 7-8)
      - Kagnew Station, 1967 (Box-folder 113: 9)
      - Lake Tana, 1950s (Box-folder 113: 10)
      - Lake Zway, 1970-2005 (Box-folder 113: 11-12)
      - Lalibela, 1967-2003 (Box-folder 113: 13)
      - Maps, 1970s-1990s (Box-folder 113: 14-16)
      - Media, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 114: 1-2)
      - Meles Zenawi, 1995-2007 (Box-folder 114: 3-4)
      - Mengistu Haile-Mariam, 1977-1991 (Box-folder 114: 5-7)
        Includes memorandum of 1977 conversation between Mengistu Haile-Mariam and Congressmen Don Bonker and Paul Tsongas.
      - Military, 1970 (Box-folder 114: 8)
      - Natural history, 1997 (Box-folder 114: 9-10)
      - Oromo language and culture, 1970s, undated (Box-folder 115: 1-2)
      - People's Democratic Republic of Ethiopia, 1987 November (Box-folder 115: 3)
      - Political parties, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 115: 4)
      - Population, 1990 (Box-folder 115: 5)
      - Postal service, 1992 (Box-folder 115: 6)
      - Provisional Military Government of Ethiopia, 1974 (Box-folder 115: 7)
        Press kit.
      - Refugees, 1976-1982 (Box-folder 115: 8)
      - Relations with the Soviet Union, 1978-1984 (Box-folder 115: 9)
      - Relations with the United States, 1969-1990
        - General, 1969-1990 (Box-folder 115: 10)
        - "Critique of U.S. Policy Toward Ethiopia,", 1977 (Box-folder 115: 11)
        - "Digest of Ethiopian Accusations Against the United States,", 1977 (Box-folder 115: 12)
        - "Military Assistance and U.S. Policy Toward Ethiopia, 1974-1976,", 1977 (Box-folder 115: 13)
        - "Overview of U.S. Military Assistance to Ethiopia from 1972 through 1976,", 1977 (Box-folder 115: 14)
        - "Questions Regarding U.S. Policy and the Ethiopian Revolution,", 1977 (Box-folder 115: 15)
      - Resettlement, 1988-2004 (Box-folder 115: 16)
      - Revolution of 1974, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 115: 17)
      - Simen Mountains National Park, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 115: 18)
      - Tigray, 1970-2001 (Box-folder 116: 1-5)
        Includes articles relating to the Tigray People's Liberation Front.
      - Transitional government, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 116: 6)
      - Villagization, 1987-1990 (Box-folder 116: 7-8)
      - Wildlife, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 116: 9)
    - Horn of Africa, 1977-1992
      - General, 1977-1996 (Box-folder 116: 10-13, Box-folder 117: 1-5)
      - State Department cables, 1974-1989 (Box-folder 117: 6-17)
        Cables related to events in Ethiopia, Somalia and Sudan.
    - Islam in Africa, undated (Box-folder 118: 1-3)
    - Kenya, 1977-1998 (Box-folder 118: 4)
    - Somalia, 1964-2009 (Box-folder 118: 5-12)
      Includes materials related to the Islamic Party of Somalia and the Somali National Movement.
    - Sudan, 1959-1995 (Box-folder 119: 1-12)
  - Clippings, 1960-2009
    On Ethiopia, Eritrea, Somalia and Sudan.
    - 1960-1979 (Box-folder 120: 1-30)
    - 1980-1984 (Box-folder 121: 1-20)
    - 1985-1989 (Box-folder 122: 1-26)
    - 1990-1992 (Box-folder 123: 1-21)
    - 1993-2009 (Box-folder 124: 1-32)
  - Printed matter, 1960-2007
    - By issuing organization, 1963-2008
      - Addis Ababa University, 1987 (Box-folder 125: 1)
      - African-American Institute, 1992 (Box-folder 125: 2)
      - African Studies Center, Michigan State University, 1979 (Box-folder 125: 3)
      - All-Ethiopia Socialist Movement, 1989 (Box-folder 125: 4)
      - American Association for Ethiopian Jews, 1987-1991 (Box-folder 125: 5)
      - Amhara Development Association, 1997 (Box-folder 125: 6)
      - Amnesty International, 1977-1978, 1991 (Box-folder 125: 7)
      - Anglo-Ethiopian Society, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 125: 8)
      - Asmara University, 1989 (Box-folder 125: 9)
      - Axumite Heritage Foundation, 1996-1999 (Box-folder 125: 10)
      - Berliner Missionswerk, 1986 (Box-folder 125: 11)
      - Catholic Relief Services, 1986 (Box-folder 125: 12)
      - Center for Foreign Journalists, Addis Ababa, 1993 (Box-folder 125: 13)
      - Center for International Peace Operations, 2008 (Box-folder 125: 14)
      - Center for Strategic and International Studies, 1991-1996 (Box-folder 125: 15)
      - Center for the Strategic Initiatives of Women, 1999 (Box-folder 125: 16)
      - Center for the Study of the Horn of Africa, 1989 (Box-folder 125: 17)
      - Central Statistical Office of Ethiopia, 1968-1990 (Box-folder 126: 1-4)
      - Coalition of Ethiopian Democratic Forces (COEDF), 1991 (Box-folder 126: 5)
      - Coalition of Peoples from Ethiopia in North America, 1987 (Box-folder 126: 6)
        Consists of anti-Derg pamphlets and flyers.
      - Commission of the European Communities in Ethiopia, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 126: 7)
      - Committee for the Founding of the People's Democratic Republic of Ethiopia, 1987 September (Box-folder 126: 8)
      - Council of Ministers of Ethiopia, 1974 Spring (Box-folder 126: 9)
        Relates to the Endelkachew Makonnen government.
      - Council of Representatives of the Transitional Government of Ethiopia, 1993 August (Box-folder 126: 10)
      - Economist Intelligence Unit, 1994, 2007 (Box-folder 127: 1)
      - Eritrean Medical Association, 1993 (Box-folder 127: 2)
      - Eritrean People's Liberation Front, 1982-1994 (Box-folder 127: 3)
      - Eritrean Relief Committee, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 127: 4)
      - The Ethiopia Society, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 127: 5)
      - Ethiopian Airlines, 1975-1994 (Box-folder 127: 6)
      - Ethiopian Chamber of Commerce, 1989-1994 (Box-folder 127: 7)
      - Ethiopian Community Development Council, 1994 (Box-folder 127: 8)
      - Ethiopian Community of Metropolitan Washington, 1988 (Box-folder 127: 9)
      - Ethiopian Congress for Democracy, 1994 (Box-folder 127: 10)
      - Ethiopian Defence League, 1991 (Box-folder 127: 11)
      - Ethiopian Democratic Union, 1976, undated (Box-folder 127: 12)
      - Ethiopian Embassy (U.S.), 1989-1996 (Box-folder 127: 13-15)
      - Ethiopian Embassy (U.S.), 1997-2004 (Box-folder 128: 1-7)
      - Ethiopian Forum for Coordinating the Struggle, 1987, 1990 (Box-folder 128: 8)
      - Ethiopian Hunger Watch Committee, 1985 (Box-folder 128: 9)
      - Ethiopian Movements for Peace, 1990 (Box-folder 128: 10)
      - Ethiopian News Agency, 1983 (Box-folder 128: 11)
      - Ethiopian Orthodox Monasteries in Jerusalem, 1982 (Box-folder 128: 12)
      - Ethiopian Peace and Unity Foundation, 1991 (Box-folder 128: 13)
      - Ethiopian People Federal Democratic Unity Party (HIBREHIZB), 1993 (Box-folder 128: 14-15)
      - Ethiopian People's Revolutionary Democratic Front (EPRDF), 1990-1992 (Box-folder 128: 16-21)
      - Ethiopian Peoples' Democratic Alliance, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 129: 1)
      - Ethiopian Peoples' Revolutionary Party (EPRP), 1984-1992 (Box-folder 129: 2-6)
      - Ethiopian Research Council, 1993 (Box-folder 129: 7)
      - Ethiopian Scientific Society (ESS), 1991-1993 (Box-folder 129: 8)
      - Ethiopian Studies Publication and Information Center (ESPIC), 1991 (Box-folder 129: 9)
      - Ethiopian Wildlife and Natural History Society, 1969-1991 (Box-folder 129: 10-14, Box-folder 130: 1-8)
      - Ethiopian Women for Peace, Development and Humanitarian Aid (EWPDHA), 1993-1996 (Box-folder 130: 9)
      - Ethiopian Women's Welfare Association, 1969 (Box-folder 130: 10)
      - Ethiopians for Constitutional Monarchy, 1991 (Box-folder 130: 11)
      - Ethiopians' Relief Organization, 1980 (Box-folder 130: 12)
      - Etiopiawinet, 1993 (Box-folder 130: 13)
      - Foreign Broadcast Information Service (FBIS), 1974-1993 (Box-folder 131: 1-11, Box-folder 132: 1-9)
      - Free People of Ethiopia, 1990 (Box-folder 132: 10)
      - Gondar Development and Cooperation Organization (GDCO), 1992 (Box-folder 132: 11)
      - Haile Sellassie I University, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 133: 1)
      - Heritage Foundation, 1989 (Box-folder 133: 2)
      - Human Rights Watch, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 133: 3)
      - Independent Committee for a Peaceful Transition to Democracy in Ethiopia, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 133: 4)
      - Institute for the Study of Ethiopian Nationalities, 1986 (Box-folder 133: 5)
      - Institute of Current World Affairs, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 133: 6)
      - International Monetary Fund (IMF), 1983-1990 (Box-folder 133: 7-8)
      - International Security Council, 1989 (Box-folder 133: 9)
      - International Union of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences, 1995 (Box-folder 133: 10)
      - Irob Relief and Rehabilitation Operations Brotherhood (IRROB), 2005-2006 (Box-folder 133: 11)
      - Maison des études éthiopiennes, 1995 (Box-folder 133: 12-13)
      - Ministry of Information, Ethiopia, 1968 (Box-folder 133: 14)
      - National Bank of Ethiopia, 1982-1987 (Box-folder 134: 1-3)
      - National Committee for Central Planning, People's Democratic Republic of Ethiopia, 1991 (Box-folder 134: 4-5)
      - National Council of Returned Peace Corps Volunteers, 1991 (Box-folder 134: 6)
      - National Endowment for Democracy, 1991 (Box-folder 134: 7)
      - National Security Archive, 1996 (Box-folder 134: 8)
      - Oklahoma-Ethiopian Assistance Group, 1992-1999 (Box-folder 134: 9-10)
      - Oklahoma State University, 1993 (Box-folder 134: 11)
      - Oromo Liberation Front, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 134: 12-13)
      - Peace Corps, 1963, 1967 (Box-folder 135: 1-2)
      - Project Mercy, 1991-1994 (Box-folder 135: 3)
      - Propaganda and Information Committee (Derg), 1978-1988 (Box-folder 135: 4)
      - RAND Corporation, 1995 (Box-folder 135: 5)
      - Relief and Rehabilitation Commission, 1990 (Box-folder 135: 6)
      - Relief Society of Tigray, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 135: 7)
      - Revolutionary Ethiopia Women's Association (REWA), 1982 (Box-folder 135: 8)
      - Smithsonian African Art Museum, 1992 (Box-folder 135: 9)
      - Société française pour les études éthiopiennes, 1969-1999 (Box-folder 136: 1-2)
      - Society of Friends of the Institute of Ethiopian Studies, 1969-1975 (Box-folder 136: 3-4)
      - Somalia Studies Association of North America, 1992 (Box-folder 136: 5)